hey guys this is evan from ez origami
and today i'll be teaching you how to
fold a paper dart from a sticky note
i've gotten a ton of requests for this
video recently so i figured i'd put
together a quick tutorial
all you need to do is prepare a single
square sheet of paper and a sticky note
will actually work really well
and i'm going to be using slightly
larger paper with color on one side and
white on the other just to make it a bit
easier to follow along
but if you're using a sticky note then
you want to hold the sticky side facing
up along this right edge here and we're
going to start by folding in half
horizontally so take this bottom edge
and fold it up to the top edge
align the corners and the edges
then make your crease
and then unfold
and now we're going to fold up this
bottom right corner by aligning the
bottom part of this right edge with the
horizontal crease that we just made
so we're going to do that by lifting up
this bottom right corner then we want to
start on the right side of the paper and
work our way over to the left aligning
the edge with that crease
once the entire edge is aligned then you
can make your crease
and now we're going to fold up this
diagonal folded edge and align it with
the same horizontal crease
and we're going to do that by again
lifting up this bottom right corner and
we want to start at the right side of
the paper and work our way over to the
left until the entire diagonal edge is
aligned with that horizontal crease
and then you can make your crease
through all layers
and then we're going to fold up the
bottom half of the model along the same
horizontal crease so we're just going to
pull it up like this
and then you can flatten everything out
and then we're going to fold up this
bottom portion once again but this time
along this diagonal folded edge here so
we're just going to lift up the bottom
portion of the model and fold it up
along that edge
and then you can make a sharp crease
through all layers
then we're going to fold the paper over
once again along this diagonal folded
edge here so we're just going to lift up
the bottom portion of the model and fold
it over to the right just like we did
before then you can flatten out the
paper and crease through all layers and
then we're going to fold this extra flap
over to the left as far as it goes so
just make your crease along this right
edge here then we're going to slightly
rotate the paper and now we're basically
going to fold the entire model in half
and we're going to do that by folding up
this bottom edge and aligning it with
this top diagonal edge here so we just
want to bring both of those edges
together and i like to start at this
right corner and work my way over to the
left you really want the paper to come
to a point at this right corner here so
just try to line up the layers like this
then keep working your way over to the
left until both of those edges are
aligned and then you can make a sharp
crease through all layers
and once you've done that then you've
finished your origami dart and to throw
it you want to hold the dart upside down
with the point facing towards you then
you want to hold it with your pointer
fingers by pushing together a little
more than halfway down from the top then
you want to flip your hands upside down
so that the dart is facing away from you
and you want to slightly push your two
fingers together and launch it in that
direction
and it does fly pretty quickly so have
fun but be careful with it and if you
like this video please give it a thumbs
up and leave a comment below
and of course subscribe to my channel
and hit the notifications bell for more
videos like this
thank you for watching and i'll see you
in the next video